Charles Green Shaw
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Miscellaneous Records, circa 1890s-circa 1970s, Series 8:; (Box 42 and packages 53-54; 0.35 linear ft.)
  Printing plates include 4 plates of a color reproduction of a painting by Shaw and 1 of a title text for "Up in Arms." Prints in Shaw's collection include 2 sets of 4 plates in 2 wrapped packages with 2 and 4 prints respectively in each set of 4. The letter opener inscription reads "John Davis Somerset Bermuda 1959."
  - Artifacts (Box 42)
    - Century Association Art Committee Medal, undated (Box 42)
    - Letter Opener with Shaw's Monogram, 1959 (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous Artifacts, undated, (in microfilm box) (Box 42)
    - Printing Plates, undated (Box 42)
    - Prints in Shaw's Collection, undated, (see: package 53) (Box 42)
    - Prints in Shaw's Collection, undated, (see: package 54) (Box 42)
  - Sound Recordings (Box 42)
    - "Some poetry recordings by Charles Shaw," undated, (magnetic tape, 6-7/8" reel) (Box 42)
    - Untitled, undated, (78 rpm?) (Box 42)
  - Prints in Shaw's Collection, undated, (see also Box 42) (Box Pkg 53)
  - Prints in Shaw's Collection, undated, (see also Box 42) (Box Pkg 54)
- Photographs, 1885-circa 1970, Series 9:; (Boxes 42-46, OV 52; 3.45 linear ft.; reel 75)
  Photographs are of artwork, people, places and miscellaneous subjects. Artwork pictured is mainly by Shaw, but there are also photographs of work by other artists as well as views of various exhibition installations. Photographs of places primarily taken by Shaw on his travels to Europe and around New York and Boston. Earlier views of Algeria and Tunis are in albums that belonged to his uncle, Frank D. Shaw. Among the miscellaneous subjects are boats and items in Shaw's collections of tinsel prints and tobacco figures. This series also contains negatives and slides.
  Photographs taken by Shaw to illustrate his writings about Boston, London, New York and Paris appear with some of those manuscripts in Series 3.
  The series is arranged as 5 subseries by subject, and chronlogically thereafter.
  9.1: Artwork, 1930s-1967
  9.2: People, 1885-circa 1970
  9.3: Places, 1888-1930s
  9.4: Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1920s-circa 1960s
  9.5: Negatives and Slides, circa 1920s-circa 1970
  - Artwork, 1930s-1967, 9.1:
    - By Shaw (Box 42)
      - Paintings, 1934-1966, undated, (see reel 75: 864-1033) (Box 42)
      - Paintings, Drawings, Collages, 1930s-1970, undated, (7 folders) (Box 42)
      - Portraits (including self portraits), 1935, undated (Box 42)
    - By Other Artists (Box 42)
      - Paintings and Drawings, undated (Box 42)
      - Sculpture, undated (Box 42)
      - Sculpture, Greek and Roman, undated, (2 folders; disbound album) (Box 42)
    - Exhibition Installations (Box 42)
      - Abstract American Artists First Exhibition, Squibb Building, New York City, 1936 (Box 42)
      - "Living with Famous Paintings," American Institute of Decorators, Los Angeles, California (Shaw not represented), 1961 (Box 42)
      - "Painting in the United States," Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh, Pa., 1945 (Box 42)
      - Shaw Solo Exhibition, Bertha Schaefer Gallery, New York City, 1963 (Box 42)
      - Shaw Solo Exhibition, Century Association, New York City, 1967 (Box 42)
      - Shaw Solo Exhibitions, Unidentified Locations, 1960s (Box 42)
      - Shaw Paintings and Fashion Mannequins in Bergdorf Goodman Windows, New York City, undated (Box 42)
      - Tinsel Prints, Addison Gallery, Andover, Mass. (many loaned from Shaw's collection), 1947 (Box 42)
  - People, 1885-circa 1970, 9.2:
    - Beebe, William, undated (Box 42)
    - Brown, Margaret Wise, undated (Box 42)
    - Carroll, Jane, circa 1922 (Box 42)
    - Gershwin, George, 1925 (Box 42)
    - Guinan, "Texas" (Mary Louise Cecilia), undated (Box 42)
    - Lewis, Sinclair, undated (Box 42)
    - Loos, Anita, circa 1925 (Box 42)
    - Luks, George (Arnold Genthe, photographer), undated (Box 42)
    - Mencken, H. L., undated (Box 42)
    - Nathan, George Jean, undated (Box 42)
    - Oelrichs, Hermann, undated (Box 42)
    - Rickard, Tex, 1925, undated (Box 42)
    - Shaw, Charles Green, 1912-1950s, (5 folders) (Box 42)
    - Shaw, Charles Green, 1960s-circa 1970, (2 folders) (Box 43)
    - Shaw, Charles Green with Others, 1911-1960s, (5 folders) (Box 43)
    - Shaw, Charles Green with Others (Yale classmates), 1914, undated, (see: Box 46 and OV 52) (Box 43)
    - Shaw, Charles Green (father), 1885, undated (Box 43)
    - Shaw Family (Frank D., uncle, and Charles Green Shaw, father, with Sallie Carr Shaw, their mother), 1881, (see also: Unidentified Individuals, possibly relatives, and Box 46) (Box 43)
    - Shaw, Frank D. (uncle), circa 1902 (Box 43)
    - Shaw, Sallie Carr (grandmother), 1880s, (see: Box 46) (Box 43)
    - Strange, Michael, undated (Box 43)
    - Taylor, Deems, undated (Box 43)
    - Tunney, Gene (Edward Steichen, photographer), circa 1926 (Box 43)
    - Unidentified Groups, 1910s (Box 43)
    - Unidentified Individuals (possibly relatives), circa 1900, undated, (see also: Shaw Family and Box 46) (Box 43)
    - Unidentified Individuals (Alden, Billie, Monty), 1920s, undated (Box 43)
    - Unidentified Individuals, undated (Box 43)
    - Shaw, Charles Green with Others (Yale classmates), 1914, undated, (see also Box 43) (Box 46 (sol))
    - Shaw, Sallie Carr (grandmother), 1880s, (see also Box 43) (Box 46 (sol))
    - Unidentified Individuals (possibly relatives), undated, (see also Box 43) (Box 46 (sol))
    - Charles Green Shaw with Others (Yale classmates), 1914, (see also Boxes 43, 46) (Box OV 52)
  - Places, 1888-1930s, 9.3:
    Travel pictures are unsorted and unidentified and include pictures of Boston, London, New York and Paris. Many of the photographs of Tunisia (belonging to Frank D. Shaw, uncle) are hand colored.
    - Algeria (album; owned by Frank D. Shaw, uncle), 1888-1889 (Box 43)
    - Boston, 1930s, undated (Box 43)
    - Copenhagen, London, 1930s, undated (Box 43)
    - London, 1930s, (5 albums in 5 folders) (Box 43)
    - New York City, undated, (2 folders) (Box 43)
    - Paris; London (album), 1930s (Box 43)
    - Paris, undated (Box 43)
    - Paris (albums), 1930s, undated (Box 43)
    - Paris, 1930s, undated, (3 albums, 3 folders) (Box 44)
    - Scandinavia; Germany; England (album), 1930s (Box 44)
    - Shaw Home, Interior Views, undated (Box 44)
    - Stockholm, 1930s (Box 44)
    - Travel Pictures, undated, (3 folders) (Box 44)
    - Travel Pictures, 1930s, (1 3 x 5 card file) (Box 44)
    - Tunisia, circa 1920, (disbound album) (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1920s-circa 1970s, 9.4:
    - Boats, 1926, undated (Box 44)
    - English Coins, undated (Box 44)
    - Figurines, undated (Box 44)
    - Shaw Collection of Broadsides, undated (Box 44)
    - Shaw Collection of Playing Cards, undated (Box 44)
    - Shaw Collection of Tinsel Prints, undated (Box 44)
    - Shaw Collection of Tobacco Figures, undated (Box 44)
    - Window Display Featuring New York – Oddly Enough by Shaw, circa 1938 (Box 44)
  - Negatives and Slides, circa 1920s-circa 1970s, 9.5:
    This subseries includes colored slides, black and white negatives and black and white lantern slides. Travel pictures are unsorted and unidentified.
    - Artwork (Box 45 (hol))
      - By Shaw, undated, (5 folders) (Box 45 (hol))
      - By Shaw, 1960-1964, undated (Box 45 (hol))
      - By Shaw, undated (Box 45 (hol))
      - By Other Artists, undated (Box 45 (hol))
    - People, Shaw, Charles Green, undated (Box 45 (hol))
    - Places, Travel Pictures, undated (Box 45 (hol))
    - Miscellaneous Subjects (Box 45 (hol))
      - Figurines, undated (Box 45 (hol))
      - Shaw Collection of Tinsel Prints, undated (Box 45 (hol))
      - Shaw Collection of Tobacco Figures, undated (Box 45 (hol))